Guide to the Timothy Hopkins Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Timothy Hopkins papers
1804-1942
1870-1935
SC1027
Hopkins, Timothy, 1859-1937.
2.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Biographical note
Timothy Hopkins was a businessman, member of the original Stanford University Board of Trustees (1885-1937), and served as president of the board (1908-1914).
Scope and Contents note
Collection includes correspondence (1804-1805, 1885-1935), daybook (1889-1928), newsclippings, and miscellaneous publications regarding the Hopkins family (1885-1935). Correspondence focuses on family matters, including the Hopkins-Searles Probate Case, Hopkins' retirement and death, and gifts to Stanford. There is also some correspondence about University matters (1896-1910). Collection also contains photographs, diplomas, memorial resolutions, published genealogies for John Hopkins and the Kellogg family, and a scrapbook kept by Hopkins of clippings on general topics, 1870-1883.
Access Terms
Clark, George T., 1862-1940.; Fairchild, David.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Jordon, David Starr, 1851-1931; Leib, Samuel Franklin, 1848-1924.; Searles, Mary F. S.; Stanford University. Board of Trustees.; William P. Wreden Books & Manuscripts (Firm); Eucalyptus--California
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, incoming from various correspondents, 1874-1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, outgoing to various correspondents, 1896-1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, outgoing to George T. Clark, 1925 Apr (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Stanford University Board of Trustees re Hopkins' letter of March 4, 1896 sugggesting a celebration to congratulate Jane Stanford upon successful Stanford Estate litigation, 1896 Mar (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence with reports, articles and research notes on Stanford University eucalyptus trees, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence re gifts from Timothy Hopkins to Stanford University, with lists [photocopies], 1893-1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, incoming to Elizabeth Hopkins, 1804-1805 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, outgoing from Mary Frances (Sherwood Hopkins) Searles, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence re Searles case, 1889-1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, E. J. Van Lennep to Nathan Van Patten re Hopkins Transportation Library, 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Book of excerpts: handwritten volume, possibly by Tim Hopkins, from multiple published sources regarding visions of mankind, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Datebook, incomplete record of events, compiled possibly Tim Hopkins, 1889-1928 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Commonplace Book: E. K. Sherwood, 1849 Mar (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lectures on English Literature: by Professor H. P. Tappan, Volume 1, compiled by Lydia Ann Sherwood (Box 1, Folder 14)
- A Sketch of the Life of Mark Hopkins, by B. B. Redding, A. L. Brancropt and Co., publishers, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Exhibition and Auction Catalogs, Estate of Mary K. Hopkins: Sherwood Hall, San Francisco Residence, and collection of Diamonds and Jewelry, circa 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- U. S. Circuit Court of Appeals, Appellants and Appellee Briefs: Norman Lee Freeman vs. Timothy Hopkins, 2 editions, 1929 Mar (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Articles - Lydia Hopkins (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Articles - Timothy Hopkins (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Articles - Searles case (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Memorial Resolution - Timothy Hopkins, Wells Fargo Bank and United Trust Company (Box 2, Folder 7)
- In Memoriam - Timothy Hopkins, Stanford Convalescent Home (bound in leather with embellishments) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Financial appraisal of Timothy Hopkins estate, 1937 Mar (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Great Barrington Book: photographs and handwritten text on Hopkins’ childhood and extended family in Great Barrington, MA (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Great Barrington Book, original notebook (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook with genealogy information and family obituaries (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Map of Great Barrington, Massachusetts (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous personal papers - public school certificates, programs, invitations, tickets, passes, membership cards, passport, illustration of fish named by Dr. Jordan "Lompochites Hopkinsi" (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Scrapbook of clippings on general topics, 1870-1883 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Certificates from Sacramento Public Schools, 1869-1873 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- In the Matter of the Probate of the Last Will and Testament of Mary F. S. Searls, Linotype Reporting and Printing Co., 1882 (Box 5)
- John Hopkins and Some of His Descendants, by Timothy Hopkins, Stanford University Press, 1932 (Box 5)
- The Kelloggs in the Old World and the New, by Timothy Hopkins, Volumes I-III, Sunset Press and Photo Engraving Co., 1903 (Box 5)